{
  "data": [
    {
      "question": "Which element forms the largest number of compounds?",
      "op_1": "Hydrogen",
      "op_2": "Oxygen",
      "op_3": "Carbon",
      "op_4": "Nitrogen",
      "ans": "Carbon"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which property of carbon leads to the formation of a large number of compounds?",
      "op_1": "Electronegativity",
      "op_2": "Catenation",
      "op_3": "Isomerism",
      "op_4": "Combustibility",
      "ans": "Catenation"
    },
    {
      "question": "How many valence electrons does carbon have?",
      "op_1": "2",
      "op_2": "3",
      "op_3": "4",
      "op_4": "6",
      "ans": "4"
    },
    {
      "question": "The unique ability of carbon to form bonds with other carbon atoms is called:",
      "op_1": "Tetravalency",
      "op_2": "Catenation",
      "op_3": "Isomerism",
      "op_4": "Combustion",
      "ans": "Catenation"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following has the general formula CnH2n+2?",
      "op_1": "Alkanes",
      "op_2": "Alkenes",
      "op_3": "Alkynes",
      "op_4": "Alcohols",
      "ans": "Alkanes"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which gas is evolved when sodium reacts with ethanol?",
      "op_1": "Oxygen",
      "op_2": "Hydrogen",
      "op_3": "Carbon dioxide",
      "op_4": "Methane",
      "ans": "Hydrogen"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which functional group is present in ethanol?",
      "op_1": "–COOH",
      "op_2": "–CHO",
      "op_3": "–OH",
      "op_4": "–CO",
      "ans": "–OH"
    },
    {
      "question": "The first member of the alkyne series is:",
      "op_1": "Methyne",
      "op_2": "Ethyne",
      "op_3": "Propyne",
      "op_4": "Butyne",
      "ans": "Ethyne"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which allotrope of carbon is used as a lubricant?",
      "op_1": "Diamond",
      "op_2": "Graphite",
      "op_3": "Fullerene",
      "op_4": "Coal",
      "ans": "Graphite"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these shows isomerism?",
      "op_1": "C2H6",
      "op_2": "C3H8",
      "op_3": "C4H10",
      "op_4": "CH4",
      "ans": "C4H10"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is the IUPAC name of CH3–CH2–OH?",
      "op_1": "Methanol",
      "op_2": "Ethanol",
      "op_3": "Propanol",
      "op_4": "Butanol",
      "ans": "Ethanol"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which compound is used for making alcoholic drinks?",
      "op_1": "Methanol",
      "op_2": "Ethanol",
      "op_3": "Propanol",
      "op_4": "Butanol",
      "ans": "Ethanol"
    },
    {
      "question": "The process of burning ethanol in air is called:",
      "op_1": "Addition reaction",
      "op_2": "Combustion",
      "op_3": "Oxidation",
      "op_4": "Saponification",
      "ans": "Combustion"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which fuel is called ‘clean fuel’?",
      "op_1": "Coal",
      "op_2": "Diesel",
      "op_3": "LPG",
      "op_4": "Petrol",
      "ans": "LPG"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which acid is present in vinegar?",
      "op_1": "Formic acid",
      "op_2": "Acetic acid",
      "op_3": "Citric acid",
      "op_4": "Oxalic acid",
      "ans": "Acetic acid"
    }
  ]
}
